



Faris Abdul Raheem

Full Stack Developer

Passionate and result-oriented Senior Software Engineer with comprehensive mastery of multiple software platforms such as JavaScript, Python, .Net, Angular, AngularJS, Java, MS SQL, CouchDB, Azure, and MEAN Stack. An avid tech enthusiast as well as a team player who loves to ideate, research, and solve problems.

WORK EXPERIENCE [4 years]

SENIOR SYSTEM ENGINEER - R&D

INFOSYS LIMITED, Mysore

01/2021 - Present

- Designed and build a full stack web application Infosys Low Code Workbench using React, Node.js, Redux, webpack, open shift console and PostgreSQL
- Enhanced the security of applications by using Keycloak
 IAM in different tech stacks- MEANJS, Node, Angular,
 Airflow, incorporated different user federation mechanisms using OpenID Connect with Active Directory and LDAP
- Consulting and handling client, Requirement analysis, packaging, setting up the environment, deploying to the client infrastructure, and solving concerns
- Designed and developed a custom IntelliSense for writing selenium test case in Eclipse using Tensor flow, Keras, GPT3 model, and Java. Improving the overall test case completion time by 25%

SYSTEM ENGINEER - R&D

INFOSYS LIMITED, Mysore

11/2018 - 12/2020

- Administered and developed 16 POC's in the team by researching and collaborating with different clients to solve their problems and improving different projects ranging through different tech stacks – Python, MEANJS, .NET, Angular, NodeJS, AngularJS
- Design and developed an Entire Full Stack Application that helps in Self-Healing of Automation Test Scripts by Al in Selenium Java using JavaScript, Angular, NodeJS, Java, and Couch DB
- Developed multiple Web Extensions in Chrome and IE for instrumenting the web application using JavaScript, Visual Basic, and NodeJS backend.
- Designed and developed custom .NET Profiler to instrument the code by open tracing methods using Custom Datadog C++ profiler, .NET, APM Server, and multithreaded logging mechanism
- Implemented DevOps CI/CD strategy to the entire team projects using Jenkins pipeline, dockerizing, Jira, and Selenium, improved overall project release time by 30%

Free Lance Developer 10/2016 - 06/2018

- Developing Web and Mobile applications for End users
- Web development using Angular JS, HTML, PHP, CSS, JS, SQL, Node.js and MongoDb
- Developed Mobile application for clients using Xamarin Forms and Ionic Framework

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages

C#, JavaScript, Python, TypeScript, SQL, HTML 5, CSS3, Java, JSON, PHP, XML, C++, C

Framework and Libraries

Angular, ASP .NET, NET Core, NodeJS, MEANJS, Angular JS, Express, Flask, Chrome Extension Development, Puppeteer, Entity Framework, Ionic, Bootstrap, jQuery

Database

MSSQL, CouchDB, Mongo DB, CouchDB, Elastic Search

Testing Tools

Nunit, Xunit, mocha, Selenium Test Automation (Java and Python), TestNG. Protractor

DevOps Tools

Docker, Git, TFS, GitHub, JIRA, Datadog, Jenkins, Google Cloud, Maven, Cloud, Azure Cloud, ELK

Familiar With

Keycloak IAM, OAUTH 2.0, IIS deployment, Node-Red, Apache Airflow, Computer Vision, Keras, TensorFlow

EDUCATION

MBA IN FINANCIAL MANAGEMENT

University of Madras 06/2020 – 06/2022 (Currently Pursuing Distance Education)

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

University of Calicut 05/2014 – 05/2018

AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Award for being Most Valuable Player of R&D team at Infosys
- Awarded for Creation of POC on Chrome Extension and Node.js
- Infosys Certified .NET CORE DEVELOPER
- Infosys Certified Python Developer
- Hackathon Winner a Hack for India 2017 v3.0 (Held at Kozhikode Cyberpark)
- Microsoft Student Partner (2015-2017)